Register to The E. Robert Schmitz Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, Series I; 4.2 linear feet (10 boxes)
  - General Correspondence, I.A
    - Mills College (Box 5, Folder 136)
      1944 Dec. 13. -- 1 item from Lynn White, jr.
      1944-1945. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.1. General Information
    - Molnar, Ferenc
    - Monteux, Pierre, 1875-1964 (Box 5; 29, Folder 137; 4)
      1922-1945
      With: Belaiev, Viktor, 1927 Feb. 28
    - Morris, Harold (Box 5, Folder 138)
      1947 Apr.-Nov. -- 3 items from Morris (Brochure enclosed)
      1947 May-Nov. -- 5 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Morse, Charles Frederic
    - Murdough, Miss ?, 1922 Apr. 11; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - Murray, Willie (Box 5, Folder 139)
      1949 June 6. -- 1 item from Murray
      1949 Apr. 26. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
      See also: SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.1. General Information
    - Murtagh, Lillian
    - Music League of America, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 140)
      1919-1922. -- 13 items from Music League (laid in: 17 financial statements (1919-1921); and 2 agreements (1920-1921))
      1920-1922. -- 17 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Music Press, Inc., 1947-1949; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Musical Courier, 1949 Jan. 6; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 141)
      2 brochures laid in
    - Muziek
      See: Pijper, Willem
    - Namura, Koichi
      See: Pro Musica Japan Center
    - National Concert and Artists Corporation (Box 5, Folder 142-146)
      1942-1949. -- 36 items from NCAC
      1942-1949. -- 70 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      1944 Aug. 2. -- 1 item from Lester O'Keefe of J. Walter Thompson
      1944 Nov. 2. -- 1 item from Henry I. Stahr, President of Hood College, to NCAC
      Also laid in: 15 contracts (1943-1948); 5 pay stubs (1943-1944); a concert schedule (1943); 4 box office statements (1943-1947); a recital statement (1949 Mar. 1); and 20 expense statements (1943-1949)
    - National Film Board of Canada. Music Department
      See: Fleming, Robert J.B.
    - National Orchestral Association, Inc.
      See: Barzin, Leon
    - Neuer, Berthold
    - New York (N.Y.). Mayor's Committee, 1929 Mar. 15; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 5)
      See also: III. PHOTOGRAPHS. Prévost, A., and the Royal Belgian Band
    - Newton, J. Earle
    - Newton, Mrs. Quigg, 1948 Mar.-May; 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 147)
      Sheet with pencil jottings laid in
    - Nijinsky, Romola de Pulszky, 1935-1938; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - Nordoff, Paul, 1909- (Box 6, Folder 149)
      [1946] Oct. 28. -- 1 item from Nordoff
      1946 Nov. 4. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - North American Prize
      See: Adashin, Harry; Bloch, Ernst; Brott, Alexander; Champagne, Claude; Fleming, Robert; Frankenstein, Alfred; Gorodnitzski, Sasha; Haubiel, Charles; Inch, Herbert; Johnson, Lockrem; Krenek, Ernst; Morris, Harold; Pentland, Barbara; Rathaus, Karl; Réti, Rudolf; Riegger, Wallingford; Schoenberg, Arnold; Somers, Harry; Stravinsky, Igor; Talma, Louise; Toch, Ernst; and Turner, Godfrey; and VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.4. North American Prize
    - Ocean Travel Bureau, 1927 June 22-24; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 150)
      Bill enclosed
    - O'Connell, Charles
    - O'Keefe, Lester
    - Opera and Concert, 1948 Sep. 27; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 150)
      Enclosure (2 copies)
    - Opéra-Comique (Paris)
      See: Ruhlman, M.
    - Oppenheimer, Selby C.
      See: McNeal, Katherine
    - Ormandy, Eugene, 1899- (Box 6, Folder 151)
      1932-1944. -- 5 items from Ormandy to E. Robert Schmitz
      1932-1933. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Ormandy
    - Paci, Mavis (Box 6, Folder 152)
      1930-1932. -- 9 items from Paci (includes 6 receipts)
      1929-1930. -- 5 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      1930 Feb. 1. -- 1 item from Podoli to Paci? (copy)
    - Palos Verdes Ranch
      See: Vanderslip, Frank A.
    - Pentland, Barbara, 1912- (Box 6, Folder 153)
      1947 Mar. 18. -- 2 items from Pentland to North American Prize (Application enclosed)
      1947 Mar.-Oct. -- 4 items from North American Prize to Pentland
    - Pettit, C.M.
    - Pfeiffer, C.H.
    - Pflugfelder, Eleanor (Box 6, Folder 153)
      1947 Aug.-Sep. -- 2 items from Pflugfelder
      1947 Sep. 9-29. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Monique Leduc
    - Philadelphia Orchestra
      See: Judson, Arthur
    - Philharmonic Society of New York
    - Phillips, Harrison, 1948 Apr. 18; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Phillips, William
    - Pica, R. Valdes
      See: Asociación Musical de Filipinas
    - Pickett, Edgar (Box 6, Folder 154)
      1931-1932. -- 7 items from Pickett (Program laid in)
      1931-1932. -- 8 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Joyce Kozloff
    - Pickett, W.L. (Box 6, Folder 154)
      1931 July 5. -- 1 item from Pickett
      1931 July 14. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Pierné, Gabriel, 1863-1937 (Box 6, Folder 155)
      [1922]-1923. -- 2 items from Pierné to E. Robert Schmitz
      1922-1924. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Pierné
    - Pijper, Willem, 1894-1947 (Box 6, Folder 156)
      1927 May-June. -- 4 items from Pijper
      1927-1928. -- 7 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Pila, Mr., 1930 Feb.-Oct.; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Pinto, Guiomar and Octavio, no date; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Piston, Walter, 1894-1976, 1946 Nov. 12; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Pleyel, 1926 Dec. 27; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Podoli, Michael (Box 6, Folder 160)
      1931-1934. -- 3 items from Podoli (includes an agreement dated 1931 Nov. 25)
      1934 Jan. 18. -- 1 item Copy of letter from Concert-direction A. Kossar, Holland, to Podoli
      1933-1934. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Pons, Lily, 1898-1976, 1944 Oct. 17; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 160)
      Photocopy [for original see: Schoenberg, Arnold, 1926 May 3]
    - Pro Arte
    - Prokofiev, Lina, 1897-, 1926 Jan. 22; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953 (Box 6, Folder 161)
      1926-1928. -- 3 items from Prokofiev to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz
      1929 May 13. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Prokofiev
      Typescript sheet labeled "November 4th, Minneapolis," with notes about bookings for Prokofiev and O'Moore laid in
    - Prokofiev, Mira, 1925 Nov. 28; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Pro-Musica, [1928] Feb. 5; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Pro-Musica (Chicago Chapter) (Box 6, Folder 162)
      1927-1932. -- 13 items from the Chapter (3 postal receipts laid in)
      1927 Mar.-Nov. -- 2 items from Bogue-Laberge to William Phillips
      1927 Mar. 1. -- 1 item from Phillips to Bogue-Laberge
      1927 Nov. 19. -- 1 item from Bogue-Laberge to the Musical Leader
      1927-1932. -- 19 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Pro-Musica (Detroit Chapter) (Box 6, Folder 163)
      1932 May-June. -- 2 items from Charles Frederic Morse
      1928 Jan.-June. -- 7 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      1928 July 30. -- 1 item from Louis Ling to Sigmund Klein
    - Pro-Musica (Honolulu Chapter), 1932 Apr.-Jan.; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 164)
    - Pro-Musica (Kansas City Chapter), 1926 Oct. 11; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 165)
    - Pro-Musica (Minneapolis Chapter), 1927 Nov. 3; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 166)
    - Pro Musica Japan Center (Box 6, Folder 167)
      1930 Aug. 3. -- 1 item from Pro Musica Japan Center
      1930 July-Oct. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Quidde, Ludwig, 1858-1941, 1914 May 11; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - RCA Victor
    - Radio Corporation of America. RCA Victor Division (Box 6, Folder 168)
      1941-1949. -- 10 items from RCA
      1941-1949. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      1941 Apr. 30. -- 1 item from A. Walter Socolow, at the request of F.W. von Meister
      Also laid in: 10 payment stubs (1942-1950); 11 royalty statements (1949-1951); and 10 agreements (1941-1945)
    - Radiodiffusion Française, 1946 June-Aug.; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 169)
      See also: Barraud, Henry
    - Rathaus, Karol, 1895-1954 (Box 6, Folder 170)
      1946 Nov. 22. -- 1 item from Rathaus
      1946 Dec. 6. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 (Box 7, Folder 171-172)
      1920-1928. -- 15 items from Ravel to E. Robert Schmitz ( Includes 2 photocopies, typed letter (copy) from Ravel to Bernard R. Laberge, and 3 envelopes)
      1922-1927. -- 20 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Ravel
      1927 Jan. -- 3 items from Pro-Musica to Daniel Mayer
      6 items: Invitation from Edisons to E. Robert Schmitz (photocopy), typescript sheet labeled "Programs Mr. Ravel will conduct for orchestras," and autograph letter signed (photocopy) from G. Jean-Aubrey to Germaine Schmitz c/o Maurice Ravel laid in
    - Reeder, Betah (Box 7, Folder 173)
      1924-1927. -- 5 items from Reeder (Music school advertisement laid in)
      1924-1927. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Reilly, Thomas M.
    - Reiner, Fritz, 1888-1963 (Box 7, Folder 174)
      1926-1945. -- 3 items Reiner to E. Robert Schmitz
      1926 Sep. 28. -- 1 item E. Robert Schmitz to Reiner
    - Reinhardt, Aurelia Henry, 1877-1948, 1945 Nov. 3; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Reis, Mrs. Arthur M.
    - Reiter, Sylvia, 1929 Dec. 17; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 175)
      Photocopy of telegram - for original see: Tansman, Alexandre
    - Reti, Rudolph, 1885-1957 (Box 7, Folder 176)
      1947-1948. -- 10 items Reti to E. Robert Schmitz (Application and postal receipt laid in)
      1947-1948. -- 10 items E. Robert Schmitz and Monique Leduc to Reti
    - Reynolds, Vicki
      See: Antheil, George; and Boyer, Charles
    - Riadis, Emile (Box 7, Folder 177)
      1930-1931. -- 3 items from Riadis
      1930-1931. -- 9 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      2 postal receipts laid in
    - Rice, Gordon K.
    - Richmond, Aaron (Box 7, Folder 178)
      1951 Mar. 28. -- 1 item from Richmond
      1944 June 16. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Riegger, Wallingford, 1885-1961 (Box 7, Folder 179)
      1946-1947. -- 5 items from Riegger (clipping laid in)
      1946-1947. -- 5 items from Monique Leduc
    - Rieti, Vittorio, 1898-, 1926-1928; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Ritte, Mr., 1922 Sep. 17; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Ritz-Carlton Hotel (N.Y.)
    - Rochemont, M. Pictet de
      See: Société de l'Orchestre de la Suisse Romande
    - Rochemont, Richard de
      See: France Forever
    - Rockefeller, Mrs. William G., [1919] June 5; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Rodzinski, Artur, 1892-1958, 1945-1946; 4 items. (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Romains, Jules, 1885-1972, 1941 Mar. 29; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Ropartz, Joseph Guy Marie, 1864-1955 (Box 7, Folder 183)
      1922-1923. -- 2 items from Ropartz
      1922-1923. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Rosenthal, Manuel, 1904-, 1948-1949; 4 items. (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937 (Box 7, Folder 185-187)
      1914-1934?. -- 50 items from Roussel to E. Robert Schmitz (includes 2 clippings, pp. 15-30 of a book or periodical about Roussel, a photograph, and an envelope laid in)
      1923-1930. -- 13 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz to Roussel
    - Rudhyar, Dane, 1895- (Box 7, Folder 188)
      1947 Feb. 10. -- 1 item from Rudhyar
      1947 Feb. 20. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Ruhlman, M., 1923 Apr. 30; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 188)
      From Ruhlman
    - Sabaneef, Leonide (Box 7, Folder 189)
      1927 May-Sep. -- 3 items from Sabaneef
      1927 June 22. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921, 1911-1914; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 190)
      Includes a photograph, a negative and a photocopy
    - Salzedo, Carlos, 1885-1961, 1927-1948; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 191)
      Ticket for 1927 May 28 performance at Maison Gaveau
      See also: Falla, Manuel de; and Stravinsky, Igor
    - Samuel, Harold E.
      See: Yale University Music Library Archival Reference File - Correspondence
    - San Francisco Chronicle
      See: Frankenstein, Alfred
    - San Francisco State College (Box 7, Folder 192)
      1949 Mar.-Apr. -- 1 item from SFSC
      1948-1949. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Monique Leduc
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND MUSIC SCHOOLS. A.1. General Information
    - Sartoris, Ceule, 1918 Dec. 5; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 192)
    - San Francisco Symphony Orchestra
      See: [Skinner], Howard
    - Schaad, H.B.
    - Schmitt, Florent, 1870-1958 (Box 7, Folder 193)
      1912-1933. -- 9 items from Schmitt to E. Robert Schmitz
      1921-1922. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Schmitt
      Typescript itinerary for Schmitt laid in
      See also: Messager, André
    - Schmitz, E. Robert (Elie Robert), 1889-1949, and Germaine, 1919-1924; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 193)
    - Schniewind, Henri and Helen (Box 7, Folder 194)
      1919-1926. -- 15 items from Schniewinds
      1919-1928. -- 33 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      Includes 2 typescript notes concerning financial matters, 6 sheets with jottings in E. Robert Schmitz's hand, 9 sheets of financial records from 1920-1925
    - Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951, 1926-1947; 4 items. (Box 7; 29, Folder 195; 7)
      typed letter signed, a photocopy, typed letter signed (photograph, negative), and typed letter (copy)
      With: Bonnet, Henri, and Pons, Lily
    - Schoettle, Elmer (Box 7, Folder 196)
      1926-1931. -- 20 items from Schoettle (2 clippings and an autograph letter signed from Elsa (Mrs. Victor H.) Anneke laid in)
      1926-1929. -- 7 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Schoettle, Gustav (Box 7, Folder 196)
      1926-1928. -- 6 items from Schoettle (clipping laid in)
      1926-1928. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Schola Cantorum of New York, 1927 Sep. 20; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - Scott, Ida Gregory (Box 7, Folder 197)
      1925-1926. -- 4 items from Scott
      1925 June 9. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Sessions, Roger, 1896-
    - Sevitzky, Fabien, 1871-1967, 1945 Dec. 22; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Seyrig, Henri
    - Shanghai (China)
    - Sherman, Clay & Co.
    - [Skinner], Howard, 1948 Dec. 6; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1894- (Box 8, Folder 199)
      1935-1936. -- 4 items from Slonimsky (Postcard to Slonimsky from the Yankee Network laid in)
      1936 May-Aug. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Smeltzer, Jeanne (Mrs. Charles B.) (Box 8, Folder 200)
      1923-1928. -- 10 items from Smeltzer
      1922-1945. -- 19 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Societá del Quartetto in Bologna, 1926 Nov. 8; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - Société de l'Orchestre de la Suisse Romande (Box 8, Folder 201)
      1922 June 4. -- 2 items from the Société... (Brochure laid in)
      1923 Mar. 20. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Société des Concerts de l'École Nationale de Musique
      See: Mariotte, A.
    - Société Internationale de Concerts
      See:
    - Société Philharmonique (Poland)
      See: Chejnacki, Mr.
    - "Philharmonia" (Paris)
      See: Sabaneef, Leonide
    - Society of the Friend [sic] of Music
      See: Takano, Takeo
    - Socolow, A. Walter
    - Soler, Augustin, 1923 Mar. 23; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - Somers, Harry, 1925- (Box 8, Folder 202)
      1943-1947. -- 4 items from Somers (includes application for NAP)
      1946-1948. -- 7 items from Monique Leduc
    - Southern California Telephone Company
    - Southwestern Musician
    - Sowerby, Leo, 1895-1968 (Box 8, Folder 203)
      1921-1922. -- 3 items from Sowerby to E. Robert Schmitz
      1922-1923. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Sowerby
    - Spindler, Mariam, 1948 May 1; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - Stahr, Henry I.
    - Stead, Franklin and Mabel Riggs (Box 8, Folder 204)
      1926-1927. -- 9 items from the Steads
      1926-1927. -- 9 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Steinberg, William, 1899-1978, 1948-1949; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 205)
      1 typed letter signed (photocopy)
    - Stevens, Halsey, 1908- (Box 8, Folder 206)
      1947 Jan. 14. -- 1 item from Stevens
      1947 Jan. 18. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Still, William Grant, 1895-, 1946 Oct. 23; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Stock, Frederick A. (Box 8, Folder 207)
      1919 Feb. 19. -- 1 item from Stock
      1919 Jan. 23. -- 2 items Draft of letter and note by E. Robert Schmitz
    - Stoes, Paul
    - Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977 (Box 8, Folder 208)
      1922-1949. -- 10 items from Stokowski to E. Robert Schmitz
      1922-1948. -- 12 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Stokowski
    - Stowitts, ?, 1935 Nov. 12; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971, and Vera (Box 8, Folder 209)
      1943-1948. -- 20 items from Stravinskys to E. Robert Schmitz, Germaine Schmitz, and Monique Leduc
      Includes 3 photocopies, 2 brochures, typescript discography and biography, 3 clippings, and typed letter (copy) from Salzedo to Stravinsky
      See also: Salzedo, Carlos
    - Szymanowski, Karol, 1882-1937 (Box 8, Folder 210)
      1926 Dec. 20. -- 2 items Szymanowski to E. Robert Schmitz (Card laid in)
      1926-1930. -- 8 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Szymanowski
      See also: B. Requests for Information from Monique Leduc. Chylínska, Teresa
    - Taft-Packwood, Gladys (Box 8, Folder 211)
      ca. 1929 Oct. 21. -- 1 item from Taft-Packwood
      1929 Oct. 21. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Tailleferre, Germaine, 1892-1983, no date; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Takano, Takeo (Box 8, Folder 213)
      1932-1948. -- 9 items from Takano to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz
      1933-1948. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      1933 Jan. 7. -- 1 item Copy of typed letter from E. Robert Schmitz to Tansman
    - Talma, Louise, 1906- (Box 8, Folder 214)
      [1947]. -- 2 items from Talma (Application form and note)
      1947-1948. -- 3 items from Monique Leduc (Announcement laid in )
      1947 Nov. 8. -- 1 item from G. Ricordi & Co. to Talma (copy)
    - Tansman, Alexandre, 1897-, and Colette (Box 8, Folder 215-219)
      1924-1953. -- 87 items from Tansmans to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz (includes photograph (negative), brochure, 5 photographs, a program, a typed letter signed from [Zab-? Turasof?], 1939 Jan. 11, 5 copies of TLs to Mr. Maxwell, Mr. E. Cools, and Bernard Laberge, a note with music by Alexandre Tansman, and a clipping)
      1927-1945. -- 17 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz to Tansmans
      4 telegrams about Tansman laid in: copy in E. Robert Schmitz's hand to Laberge, no date; from Syvlia Reiter to Germaine Schmitz, 1929 Dec. 17; and 2 from Bogue Laberge Concert Mgt. Inc. to Germaine Schmitz, 1929 Dec. 21-26
    - Tapparo, Giuseppe S. (Box 9, Folder 220)
      1927 Apr. 4-22. -- 2 items from Tapparo
      1927 Apr.-May. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Taylor, Davidson
    - Taylor, William A.
      See: Musical Courier
    - Tcherepnin, Alexander, 1899-1977, no year July 28; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 221)
    - Thomasset, Charles A. and Mary K. (Box 9, Folder 222)
      1931-1932. -- 7 items from Thomassets (Note laid in)
      1931-1932. -- 9 items from E. Robert Schmitz (includes 2 enclosures)
      See also: Klein, Sigmund
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1896- (Box 9, Folder 223)
      1945-1951. -- 15 items from Thomson (includes 1 autograph letter signed (photocopy))
      1945-1949. -- 10 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      Typescript sheet about Thomson laid in
    - Thornton, Lucile, 1929 May-June; 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 224)
    - Tibbett, Lawrence, 1896-1960, 1949 May 4-18; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 224)
      Telegrams from Tibbett, Heifetz, and Fuchs
    - Tobin, Richard M. (Box 9, Folder 224)
      1931-1932. -- 4 items from Tobin
      1931 Oct. 8. -- 1 item from Tobin to Mrs. Wilson
      1931-1932. -- 6 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Toch, Ernst, 1887-1964, and Lilly (Box 9; 29, Folder 225; 8)
      1928-1947. -- 16 items from the Tochs to E. Robert Schmitz and Monique Leduc
      Includes 1 typed letter signed (photocopy) and 2 brochures
      See also: III. PHOTOGRAPHS. Toch, Ernst
      1928-1947. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz to the Tochs
    - Travelers Insurance Company
    - Tuerk, Mr., 1928 Jan. 29; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - Turner, Godfrey, 1946 Nov. 7; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 226)
      List of composers enclosed
    - Tuteur, M.P.
      See: France Libre
    - Tuthill, [Ann?] B.
      See: Whithorne, Emerson
    - United States. Treasury Department. Internal Revenue Service (Box 9, Folder 227)
      1950 Jan. 10. -- 1 item from IRS
      1950 Feb. 6. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz, Germaine Schmitz, and Monique Leduc
      IRS form laid in
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.3. Trust Fund; and VIII.A. FINANCIAL AND LEGAL MATERIALS. Federal income tax
    - United States. Veterans Administration (San Francisco) (Box 9, Folder 227)
      1945-1948. -- 17 items from VA to Germaine Schmitz and Jean Leduc (includes forms)
      1946-1951. -- 4 items from Germaine Schmitz
      1947 June. -- 6 items Course descriptions and schedules for the Schmitz School of Piano
      1945-1949. -- 7 items Schedules, etc. for Jean Leduc
    - University of California, 1946 Dec. 11; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 227)
    - University of Southern California
      See: von KleinSmid, Rufus B.
    - Urban, Gretl
      See: Associated Music Publishers, Inc.; and Carl Fischer, Inc.
    - Valerio, A.
    - Van Cleef, Robert (Box 9, Folder 228)
      1923 Apr. 17. -- 1 item from Van Cleef
      1923 May-June. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Vanderslip, Frank A. (Box 9, Folder 228)
      1931 Mar. 10. -- 1 item from Vanderslip
      1931-1932. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Varèse, Edgar, 1883-1965 (Box 9, Folder 229)
      1927 June-Aug. -- 2 items from Varèse to E. Robert Schmitz
      1927 May 20. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz to Varèse
      See also: Falla, Manuel de
    - Vendôme, La Duchesse de, 1913 Dec. 12; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 230)
    - Verhuyck-Coulon, G.
    - Victor Talking Machine Company
      See also: Kodály, Zoltán
    - Victoria Theatre (Singapore)
      See: Gilmore, Arthur
    - von der Goltz, Eric
    - von KleinSmid, Rufus B. (Box 9, Folder 230)
      1932 May 4. -- 1 item from von KleinSmid
      1932 Apr. 16-29. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - von Meister, F.W.
      See: General Anilene & Film Corporation. Ozalid Products Division; and Radio Corporation of America. RCA Victor Division
    - Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962, 1946 Jan. 1; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - Waring, Fern Williams (Box 9, Folder 231)
      1931-1932. -- 3 items from Waring
      1931-1932. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz
    - Weill, Pierre-André
    - Weintraub, Eugene
    - Wentworth, R.C.
      See: General Anilene & Film Corporation. Ozalid Products Division
    - White, Lynn, jr.
      See: Mills College
    - Whithorne, Emerson, 1884-1958 (Box 9, Folder 232)
      1923-1936. -- 7 items from Whithorne to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz
      1926 May 22. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz to Whithorne
      1 item typed letter signed from Composers' Music Corporation to Germaine Schmitz, 1923 June 5, concerning Whithorne, laid in
      1923 Apr. 2. -- 1 item from [Ann?] B. Tuthill to Whithorne
    - Witte, Roland R.
      See: Horner-Witte Concert Bureau, Inc.
    - Wittgenstein, Paul, 1907-
    - Wolfe, Florence
    - Wolff, Albert, 1884-1970, 1930 Feb.-Oct.; 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - Wright, Cobina (Mrs. William M.), 1931 Dec. 12; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - Wulsin, Eugene, 1948 May 1; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - Wulsin, Lucien, 1941 Jan. 7; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - Wyman, Philip
    - Yale University Music Library